TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
네, 텐료 집입니다.
Hello? This is Tenryo.
아, 시원하다. 이런 날엔 집에 있는게 딱이야!
This feels so cool. Staying in home is the best thing to do in a day like this!
그래, 여기에 차가운 아이스크림도 있으면 최고일 거야!
Yeah, if we had some ice creams, then it could be better!
넌 못 먹잖아.
You can't eat.
임마, 바보야, 분위기란 거야, 분위기!
Don't you get that it's a matter of the atmosphere?!
잠깐, 잇키, 메타비?
Hey, Ikki and Metabee?
어, 왜?
Uh, why?
지금 아빠한테서 전화가 왔어. 중요한 서류를 가져가는 걸 잊어서 회사에 가져다 달래.
Your dad called me. He said that he forgot to bring an important paperwork and he wants you
to take it to the company.
어? 이런 더운 날에 밖에 나가기 싫어!
What? I don't want to go outside in a hot day like this!
그래도 3시 회의에 이게 없으면 아빠 모가지일 수도 있어.
But if he doesn't get this by 3, he might get fired.
어?! 모가지?!
What?! Fired?!
그렇게 되면 다음 달 잇키 용돈 못 주게 돼.
If that happens, we can't give you allowance from next month.
택배 대소동
Uproar over Delivery
(en: Delivery Boy)
100! 자, 메타비! 가위바위보 해!
100! Now, Metabee, do a rock-scissor-paper!
어, 벌써 100보야? 너 꾀 부리는 거 아냐?
What, 100 steps already? Aren't you cheating?
아니야! 자, 가위바위보!
No, I am not! Just do a rock-scissor-paper!
가위바위보! 무승부, 다시!
Rock-scissor-paper! Draw and again!
무승부, 다시!
Draw and again!
아싸! 이겼다! 자, 이번엔 메타비 차례!
Yay! I won! Here! It's your turn now, Metabee!
칫.
Tch.
아, 덥고 어깨는 뻐근하고!
It's hot and my shoulder is stiff!
어! 긴카이.
What the?! Ginkai!
빨리 사과해 둘까.
I should apologize right now.
급했으니 용서해!
We were in hurry, so forgive us!
안 돼! 그 싸움 잘 받아 주겠다!
No way! I will accept your challenge for a fight!
아니, 안 줬는데요.
The thing is I didn't ask...
데스 메다로트 전송! 로빈 아치!
Transfer Death Medarot! Robin Arch!
RBA형 로빈 아치
RBA Type Robin Arch
로보틀로 승부다!
Do a Robattle with me!
어째, 잇키.
What should we do, Ikki?
무엇보다도 시간이... 이걸 어쩐담...
We don't have much time... what should we do?
너, 빨리 안 하면 용돈 없어지잖아?
You're gonna lose your allowances if you don't hurry!
그러면 메타비 파트도 탄환도 못 사게 되고...
And if that happens, I won't be able to buy parts and bullets for you, Metabee...
그리고 다시는 로보틀 못 하게 되겠지.
And we won't be doing Robattles anymore.
그렇게 되지.
You are right.
왜 그래? 안 덤벼들 거 라면 나부터 한다!
What's wrong? If you aren't going to start, then I will!
어쩌냐, 잇키!
What should we do, Ikki?!
메타비, 나한테 좋은 생각이 있어.
Metabee, I have a good idea.
알겠어? 이럴 땐 말야...
Listen. In a time like this...
야! 뭘 조잘조잘대고 있냐!
Hey! What are you babbling about?!
-응, 응!
-그러니까...
-Yeah, yeah!
-and that's why...
어이! 이상한 생각 마!
Hey! Don't even think about it!
좋아, 알겠어!
Alright, I got it!
메타비, 하나 둘에 셋 하면 간다!
Metabee, let's go at one, two, and three!
하나!
One!
둘에!
Two and!
철수.
Withdraw.
어이, 야! 멈춰! 도망가지 말고 승부 봐!
Hey, you guys! Stop! Don't run away and face me!
바보, 달아나는 게 이기는 거다!
You fool! Running away is winning!
멈춰라!
Stop!
안 되겠어! 우릴 쫒아오잖아!
This isn't good! He's chasing us!
에이, 도망쳐!
Just run!
멈춰!
Stop!
-이쪽이야!
-응!
-This way!
-Right!
아, 저기다!
They're there!
끈질기네, 쟤들!
They're so persistent!
달아나게 두지 않을 테다!
You aren't getting away!
로빈 아치! 보우건 매그넘!
Robin Arch! Bow Gun Magnum!
조심해, 메타비! 쟤냬가 노리고 있어!
Be careful, Metabee! They're onto us!
젠장! 로빈 아치, 넌 저 쪽으로!
Damn! Robin Arch, you can go that way!
어이, 봐봐, 잇키! 긴카이밖에 없어!
Hey, look, Ikki! Only Ginkai is behind us!
방심하지 마! 어딘가에 있을 거야!
Don't let your guards down! It should be somewhere!
보우건 매그넘!
Bow Gun Magnum!
해냈다!
I did it!
메타비! 괜찮아!
Metabee! Are you alright?
어, 그런가 봐.
Yeah, probably.
잘됐네! 무사하구나!
Great! You're safe!
아무것도 아니네. 가자. 야.
That was nothing. Let's go. Hey.
야, 멈춰, 야! 난 어떻게 되든 상관없다는 거냐!
Hey, stop! Do you even care about me at all?!
-멈춰라!
-누가 멈추냐!
-Stop!
-Nobody would!
-메타비, 블래스터야! 막 쏴!
-어!
-Metabee, use your blaster! Shoot as much as needed!
-Right!
여긴 가게 안이야! 다른 손님에게 피해 안 가게 충분히 조심해!
We're in a store! Be careful as we might trouble other customers!
알아, 알아!
I know that, I know that!
그런 게 통할 것 같냐!
That will never work!
파트 전송!
Transfer Part!
그 바디를 조각조각 잘라 주겠어!
I will cut your body into pieces!
젠장!
Damn!
메타비, 너무 쏘지 마! 탄환 다 쓰겠다!
Metabee, don't shoot too much! You're gonna use all your ammo!
나보고 쏘라는 거야 말라는 거야?!
Do you want me to shoot or not?!
메타비! 여기, 여기!
Metabee, here, here!
시식 코너
Free Sample Stand
-꽤 하네!
-그러게, 데스 메다로트 무섭네.
-They're pretty good!
-Yeah, Death Medarots are formidable!
아, 젠장! 야, 멈춰!
Oh, right! Hey, you brat, stop!
이 자식들아! 가게 안에서 로보틀하면 안 된다!
You brats! No Robattles in stores!
죄송합니다!
I'm sorry!
키쿠히메, 딱 적당한 때에 왔어! 너 보고 싶었단 말야! 헤!
Kikuhime, you're here at the perfect time! I wanted to see you, you know!
뭐야, 기분 나쁘게!
That's disgusting!
자, 나머지는 알아서 잘 부탁해! 헤헤.
The rest is up to you! Heh.
자, 나머지는 알아서 잘 부탁해!
The rest is up to you!
뭐야, 잘 부탁한다니!
What do you mean by that?!
멈춰라! 비켜비켜비켜!
Stop! Movemovemove!
멈춰라!
Stop!
기능 정지입니다.
We have stopped working.
-서둘러라!
-네, 형님!
-Hurry!
-Understood, bro!
어, 어이, 서둘러라!
H- hey, hurry!
괜찮아, 메타비?
Are you alright, Metabee?
어...
Yeah...
어, 뭐야, 이건?
Huh? What's this?
은행 강도다!
Bank robbers!
봤겠다!
You've seen us!
어? 몰라몰라! 안 보여, 안 보여!
Huh? I don't know anything! I've seen nothing!
응, 응!
Yeah, yeah!
아, 있다, 잇키!
Hey, Ikki's here!
아까는 잘도 내 체면을 죽였겠다! 페퍼캣, 파트 전송!
You dared to disgrace me! Peppercat, Transfer Part!
각오는 됐겠지?
I hope you're prepared!
또 도망쳐!
Run again!
야, 멈춰!
Hey, stop!
아, 저기 있다!
Hey, they're there!
아, 안 되겠어! 우리도 튀자!
This is bad! Let's run too!
네!
Right!
아, 틀렸어요, 형님!
This won't work, bro!
타이어에 펑크났어요.
There's a puncture in tire.
잇키, 나 달아나는 거 지쳤어! 싸우자!
Ikki, I'm tired of running away! Let's fight!
안돼, 메타비! 시간이 없어!
No, Metabee! We don't have much time!
알 게 뭐야! 달아나는 건 관둘래!
I don't care! I'm fed up with running!
이렇게 된 바 뭔 소리를 듣든 난 끝까지 싸우겠어!
As this happened, I will fight to the very end!
메타비! 용돈 없어져도 돼?!
Metabee! What about the allowance?!
나하고 전혀 관계 없어.
It has nothing to do with me.
탄환도 파트도 못 사게 돼!
We won't be buying any ammo or parts anymore!
그 때는 네가 어떻게든 해!
You do something when that happens!
부수어져도 나에 씨에게 공짜로 수리받을 수밖에 없게 돼! 엄청 못나보일 거야!
Even if you get destroyed, we'll have to ask Ms. Nae to fix you for free! That will be totally uncool!
정말...
Damn...
느려, 잇키! 어서 도망쳐!
You're slow, Ikki! Hurry up and run!
잠깐만! 이 서류가방이라도 좀 들고 가!
Wait! At least you can take this briefcase with you!
젠장, 이렇게는 못 달아나겠어.
Damn, we can't run away at this rate.
형님, 큰일이에요!
Bro, we have a problem!
어이, 조용히 해! 그러단 들킨다!
Hey, be quiet! You might get us discovers!
이런 때는 침착하게 행동해야만 한다.
We must act calmly at times like this.
그, 그래도, 형님...
B- but, bro...
진짜 나쁘다는 건 말야, 싸구려같이 행동하다 놀라거나 크게 소리지르거나 하는 게 아니다!
To be truly evil, you must not act cheap, get surprised, or speak loudly!
그래서 왜 그러냐?
So, what's the problem?
돈이 서류로 바뀌었어요.
The money became paperworks.
뭐, 뭐라고?!
W- what?!
그럴 리가! 그런 일이 일어날 리가 없잖아! 더 열심히 찾아봐, 찾아봐!
No way! That is impossible! Find it! Find it more deeply!
여기서 이 종이를 떼면 여기... 아, 없어, 내 돈이...
Remove this paper from here and there's... damn, no money of mine!
형님, 침착해요, 침착! 침착해요, 형님!
Brother, calm down, be calm! Calm down, brother!
아, 아까 그 꼬맹이다! 그 놈들이 서류가방을 바꾸어 가져간 거야!
I see! That brat before must have confused the briefcases and took the wrong one!
어째요, 형님.
What should we do, brother?
멍청한 자식! 찾는 게 당연하잖아! 뭔 일이 있어도 그 돈을 되찾는 거야!
You idiot! We'll take it back the money no matter what!
그, 그래도, 형님, 밖에 짭새가 우글우글거리고 있어요.
B- but, brother, there are many polices outside!
어?
Huh?
어라, 걔냬들 안 쫒아오고 있어.
Hey, they aren't chasing us anymore.
어, 정말이네! 다행이야! 겨우 포기했구나!
Hey, you're right! What a relief! They finally gave up!
그렇구나! 우리가 도망치는 건 못 따라오는 거구나!
I see! They can't follow us when we're running away in full speed!
헤, 그렇지! 따라올 수 있다면 따라와 보시지!
Yeah, right! Catch us if you can!
얘들아, 해라!
You kids, do whatever you want!
어, 땡큐, 아저씨!
Yeah, thank you, mister!
으에! 더러워! 그런 게 어디 있어!
That's dirty! That's so bad!
아, 저깄어요, 형님! 저기, 저기!
They're there, bro! Over there!
은행 강도!
Bank robbers!
어이, 아무것도 안 할 테니까 순순히 그 서류가방을 넘겨주지 않을래?
Hey, I won't do anything if you hand over that briefcase.
서, 서류가방?
B- briefcase?
어이, 속으면 안 돼, 잇키. 이건 분명 뭔가 있어.
Hey, don't be fooled, Ikki. There is something finish going on here.
그렇지. 은행 강도가 이런 걸 원할 리가 말야...
You're right. There is no way bank robbers would want this...
그 말은 우리가 유일한 목격자라는 거야!
That means we're the only eyewitnesses!
어?
Huh?
위험해! 도망쳐!
That's bad! Run!
잡히면 죽을 거야!
They'll kill us if they get us!
그런 건 안 말해도 알아!
No need to tell me that!
멈춰라! 도둑!
Stop that thief!
멈춰!
Stop!
지명수배 중인 강도 2명 발견! 즉시 뒤쫒으라!
Two wanted thieve found! Chase them!
승부해!
Fight me!
사과해!
Apologize!
도둑!
Thief!
젠장, 뭐야?! 난 그냥 아빠한테 서류를 전할 생각인데!
Damn it, what is this?! I was just trying to take this briefcase to dad!
음양 역
Ginjou Station
역이야! 타자, 메타비!
A station! Let's get in, Metabee!
알았어!
Got it!
어디, 아빠 회사는 다음 역이니까 90엔.
Well, my dad's company is at the next station, so 90 yen.
90엔.
90 yen.
어?
Huh?
90엔, 90엔이라.
90 yen, 90 yen it is.
뭐야?!
What the-?!
주위는 완전히 포위됐다. 소용없는 저항은 관두고 나와라!
You are completely surrounded. Stop the futile resistance and surrender!
젠장, 짭새군.
Damn, the police is here!
어떻게 된 거야? 설마 우리 체포되는 거야?
What's going on? Are we gonna be arrested?
어이, 잇키! 3시까지 앞으로 20분밖에 없어!
Hey, Ikki! We only have 20 minutes 'till 3'o clock!
어쩔 수 없지. 도망쳐!
It can't be helped. Run!
쫒아!
Get them!
형님, 같이 가요!
Bro, wait for me!
쫒아! 역에 돌입해라!
Chase them! Get into the station!
예!
Yessir!
어디, 표, 표라...
The tickets, the tickets...
지금 1호선 열차가 역에 들어오고 있습니다.
The train for the 1st Line is now approaching.
어디 갔냐!
Where did they go?!
어떻게 해서든 찾아내!
Find them no matter what!
안 되겠어! 우물쭈물대고 있다간 잡히겠어!
This is bad! We're gonna be caught if we hesitate!
어?!
Huh?
아, 형님! 저기 있어요!
Look, bro! Over there!
로빈 아치! 파트 전송!
Robin Arch! Transfer Part!
돈 돌려줘!
Give my money back!
트라이트루퍼 발사!
Fire Tritrooper!
아야야야!
Ouch!
이때다! 도망쳐!
Now's the chance! Run!
멈춰!
Stop!
형님, 정신 차려요! 눈앞이에요!
Get a grip, bro! We're almost there!
이런 곳에서 로보틀하지 마라!
Don't do Robattles at a place like this!
전차 내에서의 흡연, 전화, 로보틀 등의 일은 손님께 폐를 끼치니 삼가 주시기 바랍니다.
Smoking, calling, and Robattles in train cause inconveniences to the customers, so please refrain from doing so.
가라, 메타비!
Go, Metabee!
뭔 짓이야! 로보틀 방해하지 마!
What was that for?! Do not interrupt our Robattle!
시꺼! 애초에 슈퍼에서 날 밟고 지나갔으니 그렇게 된 거잖아!
Shut up! It all happened because you ran and stepped over me in the supermarket at the first place!
어? 그건 그게...
Oh, about that, you know...
메, 메타비!
M- Metabee!
지금이다! 베어버려, 로빈 아치!
Now! Cut him off, Robin Arch!
피해, 메타비!
Evade, Metabee!
피해!
Evade!
이 자식!
You bastard!
해냈어, 잇키! 쉽네!
I did it, Ikki! It was easy!
정말, 조마조마하게 한다니까!
Really, you make me nervous!
조심해, 메타비!
Look out, Metabee!
메타비!
Metabee!
해냈어! 드디어 해치웠다!
I did it! I finally got rid of him!
방해하더니 잘 됐다!
That's what you get for getting in my way!
메타비.
Metabee.
그렇게 간단히 당할까보냐! 난 아직 안 끝났어!
I won't be taken down that easily! I am not over yet!
메타비...
Metabee...
이번에야말로 끝내주겠어!
I will finish you up this time!
현재 강도범 추적중.
Currently in pursuit of the robbers.
뭐, 뭐야, 저건?!
W- what's that?!
메타비! 발을 조준해!
Metabee! Aim at its foot!
시꺼! 알아!
Shut up! I know that!
뭐, 뭐야? 전차 위에서 하고 있어?
W- what's this? They're fighting on the train?
보여줘, 보여줘!
Show us, show us!
그래, 힘내, 잘 해라! 응원한다!
Do your best! I'm cheering for you!
해, 해 버려!
Do it! Finish this!
아, 저기 있다! 그 꼬맹이! 비켜, 비켜!
Hey, that brat is over there! Move, move!
-끼어들지 마!
-답답하게!
-Don't push!
-Where's your manners?!
이게!
That bastard!
지하에 들어갔다! 추적 불가능!
They went underground! Unable to pursue!
저런!
Damn!
승부 났네.
The match is set.
끝장이다!
Finish!
이판사판이다! 메타비, 다리를 쏴!
Whatever goes now! Metabee! Aim at the legs!
좋아!
Right!
이랴!
Take this!
해냈어.
I did it.
봤냐! 헤, 승부 났다!
Did you see?! Heh, this is how the match ends!
야, 키쿠히메, 너 누구 편이냐?
Hey, Kikuhime, whose side are you on?
강한 쪽.
The stronger side.
서둘러, 메타비! 앞으로 10분밖에 없어!
Hurry, Metabee! We only have 10 minutes remaining!
좋아!
Right!
도망치게 두지 마라! 이번에야말로 잡아라!
Don't let them get away! Get them this time!
어, 잇키! 잠깐!
Hey, Ikki, wait for me!
죄송합니다! 내릴게요!
Excuse me! I'm getting off!
아, 내려요! 내려요!
No! I'm getting off! I'm getting off!
잇키, 어디야, 아버님 회사는?!
Ikki, where is the father's company?!
저거야!
That is it!
여기야! 드디어 왔다!
Finally! We're here!
로빈 아치.
Robin Arch.
마지막 승부를 봐라!
Have a final match against me!
젠장! 끈질긴 놈들!
Those damn persistent guys!
여기라면 누구한테도 방해받지 않고 로보틀할 수 있어!
At here, we can have a Robattle without being interrupted by anyone!
이제 관둬, 긴카이! 로빈 아치가 받은 피해가 너무 커!
Forget that, Ginkai! Robin Arch has taken too much damage!
이 이상 하면 정말 부서진다!
If you over do it, it's gonna be broken completely!
네가 알 바냐! 설마 로빈 아치가 재기 불능이 되더라도 너희들한테 이길 수 있다면 그걸로 됐어!
Like hell you care! Even if Robin Arch becomes disabled past hope of recovery, if I can defeat you guys, that's good enough!
긴카이.
Ginkai.
각오해라!
Prepare yourself!
끼어들지 말고 비켜라!
Get out of my way!
이번에야말로 못 도망친다!
You aren't getting away this time!
으엑! 더 끈질긴 놈이 왔다!
Daaaamn! They're even more persistent ones!
잇키, 시간이 없어! 로보틀은 나한테 맡기고 어서 아버님한테 가!
Ikki, we have no time! Leave the Robattle to me and go meet your father right now!
그래, 알았어! 부탁할게, 메타비!
Alright, got it! Please do so, Metabee!
파트 전송!
Transfer Part!
대회의실은 어디에요?
Where is the Grand Meeting Room?
어? 12층입니다만.
Huh? It's on the 12th floor.
감사합니다!
Thanks!
젠장! 계단이다!
Damn! We're going by stairs!
잇키, 아직이냐...
Ikki, not yet?
힘내, 메타비!
Keep it up, Metabee!
형님, 이제 틀렸어요!
Bro, I can't do this anymore!
힘내! 칠칠치 못하게. 그거 넘겨라, 꼬맹아!
Keep it up! Where's your discipline?! Hand that over, you brat!
좋아, 좋아, 그 기세야!
Great, great! That's the spirit!
0!
이 자식!
You're going down!
얌전히 있어라!
Keep calm!
아, 아빠... 여기.
D- dad... here.
고맙다, 잇키.
Thank you, Ikki.
어?
Huh?
대체 어떻게 된 거야?
What happened?
이제 시간이 되었으니 회의를 시작하겠습니다.
Since it's time, I'd like to begin the discussion.
이게 서류가 아니면 내가 들고다닌 건 대체 뭐야?
If this doesn't contain paperwork, then what did I carry?
뭐뭐뭐뭐, 뭐야, 이거!
W-w-w-w- what's this?!
범인 체포에 협력해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Thank you for cooperating with chasing the criminals.
덕분에 전금을 되찾을 수 있었습니다.
Thanks to you, we could take back all the stolen money.
그럼.
Then.
어?
Huh?
대체 뭐가 어떻게 된 걸까?
I still don't know what happened.
그래도 서류가 제 시간에 도착했으니 됐잖아?
But still, since the paperwork made it in time, so it doesn't matter!
이걸로 잇키 용돈도 안 사라지겠네.
Now your allowance is safe, Ikki!
그것도 그렇네.
Yeah, you're right.
자, 어서 돌아가자! 어머님이 기다리고 계셔!
Now let's hurry our way back! Our mother is waiting for us.
어!
Yeah!
여기 어디야?
Where are we?
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
음양 초등학교에서 갑자기 일어난 신문부와 방송부의 특종 결전.
A sudden scoop showdown has happened in Ginjou Elementary School.
궁지에 몰린 단 하나의 신문부원 아리카는 스캔들 취재에 열중.
The only staff of the newspaper club, Arika, is devoted to news gathering.
그런 아리카를 걱정해서 고장날 때까지 로보틀한 브라스.
Worried about Arika, Brass did a Robattle until she goes over a breakdown.
적은 데스 메다로트, 플레임캐스트.
The enemy is Death Medarot named Flamecast.
과연 브라스의 진심이 아리카에게 전해질 것인가!
Will Brass' devotion be conveyed to Arika?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 결전! 특종 전투
Next time on Medarot: Spirits! Showdown! Scoop Fight
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!